# JONATHAN "JEN" MCQUADE

### FRONTEND DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT

Full stack development with a decade of experience building unique, branded Web sites and promotional emails in high-volume, fast-paced software sprints. Engineer of jQuery "Child Sponsorship Web Services" plugin for World Vision, USA. Helped increase online revenue by 5% using A/B testing of landing pages. Managed automated build releases for four digital products using Atlassian Bamboo. Lead developer in team of four.

## **Experience**

### 2016 – Present

## **Independent Web Consultations**

- mountangelabbey.org Word Press theming (contracted through SiteCrafting, Tacoma)
- evilkittehstudios.com Word Press design and theming
- shockedandapplaud.com Artwork design, Content Producer, Sound Engineer, Social Media Marketing

### 2008 -2016

# Full Stack Internet Developer

World Vision, USA

- PHP Content Management system updates (Drupal)
- Knowledge expert in PHP Web Service middleware
- Consultations with Senior Designers on style guide implementations across multiple properties
- Korean localization of Magento Ecommerce site
- PSD to HTML, CSS/SASS/LESS, JavaScript pages on over two dozen marketing campaigns w/ integrated analytics, A/B split testing, video, mobile-first design
- Daily Agile & SCRUM standups, sprint planning
- QA team collaboration on release management
- 6+ months full time working from home

# 2006 -

## **Contracted Web Content Producer**

2008 Volt Technical Group

- Branded email production and automation
- Landing page production for marketing campaigns
- worldvision.org homepage updates

### 2002 -2003

## Developer Intern

starbucks.com

- Bug tracking and fixing using version control
- Marketing email production, design collaboration

## **Education**

## 2000 – Highline College

2002

AAS in Interactive Media, honors Story building, graphic design, Web design, development

## **Personal Info**

### Address

1273 S 315<sup>th</sup> St Federal Way, WA 98003

### **Email**

jen.k.mcquade@gmail.com

#### **WWW**

jmcquade.com

### Phone

(253) 204-0075

## **Skills**





Over 10 years of branded emails and templating.



8 years custom events, jQuery plugins, 1 year ReactJS



4 years custom PHP Web Services, Drupal, WordPress, Magento

- Photoshop & Illustrator (1 yr)
- SCRUM & Agile Software (5 yr)
- Git (5 yr)